<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<threatsDefinitions xmlns="https://www.tas.org/threat-definition"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.tas.org/threat-definition file:/D:/Master/work/TAS/TAS-Solution/src/main/resources/com/tas/schemas/ThreatsSchema.xsd">
    
    <threatDefinition id="1">
        <name>Cross Site Request Forgery</name>
        <category>Elevation Of Privilege</category>
        <shortDescription>
            Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) is an attack that forces an end user to execute 
            unwanted actions on a web application in which they're currently authenticated.
        </shortDescription>
        <longDescription>
            Cross-site request forgery (CSRF or XSRF)<link address="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)">
            (more information here)</link>  is a type of attack in 
            which an attacker forces a user's browser to make a forged request to a vulnerable 
            site by exploiting an existing trust relationship between the browser and the 
            vulnerable web site.  In a simple scenario, a user is logged in to web site A 
            using a cookie as a credential.  The other browses to web site B.  Web site B 
            returns a page with a hidden form that posts to web site A.  Since the browser 
            will carry the user's cookie to web site A, web site B now can take any action 
            on web site A, for example, adding an admin to an account.  The attack can be 
            used to exploit any requests that the browser automatically authenticates, e.g. 
            by session cookie, integrated authentication, IP whitelisting, …  The attack can be 
            carried out in many ways such as by luring the victim to a site under control of the 
            attacker, getting the user to click a link in a phishing email, or hacking a reputable 
            web site that the victim will visit. The issue can only be resolved on the server side 
            by requiring that all authenticated state-changing requests include an additional piece 
            of secret payload (canary or CSRF token) which is known only to the legitimate web site 
            and the browser and which is protected in transit through SSL/TLS. See the Forgery 
            Protection property on the flow stencil for a list of mitigations.
        </longDescription>
        <severity>3</severity>
        <reference>https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)</reference>
        <preventions>
            <prevention>
                <name>Using a secret cookie</name>
                <description>
                    Remember that all cookies, even the secret ones, will be submitted with every 
                    request. All authentication tokens will be submitted regardless of whether or 
                    not the end-user was tricked into submitting the request. Furthermore, session 
                    identifiers are simply used by the application container to associate the request 
                    with a specific session object. The session identifier does not verify that the 
                    end-user intended to submit the request.
                </description>
                <reference>https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)#Using_a_secret_cookie</reference>
            </prevention>
            <prevention>
                <name>Only accepting POST requests</name>
                <description>
                    Applications can be developed to only accept POST requests for the execution of 
                    business logic. The misconception is that since the attacker cannot construct a 
                    malicious link, a CSRF attack cannot be executed. Unfortunately, this logic is 
                    incorrect. There are numerous methods in which an attacker can trick a victim 
                    into submitting a forged POST request, such as a simple form hosted in an attacker's 
                    Website with hidden values. This form can be triggered automatically by JavaScript or 
                    can be triggered by the victim who thinks the form will do something else.
                    
                    A number of flawed ideas for defending against CSRF attacks have been developed over 
                    time. Here are a few that we recommend you avoid.
                </description>
                <reference>https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)#Only_accepting_POST_requests</reference>
            </prevention>
        </preventions>
    </threatDefinition>
    
    <threatDefinition id="2">
        <name>Replay Attacks</name>
        <category>Tampering</category>
        <shortDescription>Packets or messages without sequence numbers or timestamps can be captured and 
            replayed in a wide variety of ways. Implement or utilize an existing communication protocol 
            that supports anti-replay techniques (investigate sequence numbers before timers) and strong 
            integrity.
        </shortDescription>
        <longDescription>
            A replay attack is a "man-in-the-middle" type of attack where a message is intercepted and 
            replayed by an attacker to impersonate the original sender. For web services, as with other 
            types of HTTP traffic, a sniffer such as Ethereal or Wireshark can capture traffic posted to 
            a web service and using a tool like WebScarab, a tester can resend a packet to the target 
            server. A tester can attempt to resend the original message or change the message in order 
            to compromise the host server.
        </longDescription>
        <severity>3</severity>
        <reference>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Replay_attack</reference>
        <preventions>
            <prevention>
                <name>One-time passwords</name>
                <description>
                    One-time passwords are similar to session tokens in that the password 
                    expires after it has been used or after a very short amount of time. They can 
                    be used to authenticate individual transactions in addition to sessions. These 
                    can also be used during the authentication process to help establish trust between 
                    the two parties that are communicating with each other.
                </description>
                <reference>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Replay_attack#One-time_passwords</reference>
            </prevention>            
            <prevention>
                <name>Timestamps</name>
                <description>
                    Timestamping is another way of preventing a replay attack. Synchronization should 
                    be achieved using a secure protocol. For example Bob periodically broadcasts the 
                    time on his clock together with a MAC. When Alice wants to send Bob a message, she 
                    includes her best estimate of the time on his clock in her message, which is also 
                    authenticated. Bob only accepts messages for which the timestamp is within a reasonable 
                    tolerance. The advantage of this scheme is that Bob does not need to generate (pseudo-) 
                    random numbers, with the trade-off being that replay attacks, if they are performed 
                    quickly enough i.e. within that 'reasonable' limit, could succeed.
                </description>
                <reference>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Replay_attack#Timestamps</reference>
            </prevention>
            
        </preventions>
    </threatDefinition>
    
</threatsDefinitions>